Guide to the Annie Warburton Goodrich Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Annie Warburton Goodrich papers
1876-1952
MS 1308
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8
(8 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, photographs, nursing curriculum and memorabilia of Annie Warburton Goodrich. Also included are records of the Committee on Nursing Organization.
Goodrich, Annie Warburton, 1866-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Yale University Historical Medical Library, 1980.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, photographs, nursing curriculum and memorabilia of Annie Warburton Goodrich. Also included are records of the Committee on Nursing Organization.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence and Papers. II. Photographs and Memorabilia.
Nursing; Nurses; Goodrich, Annie Warburton, 1866-
- CORRESPONDENCE AND PAPERS, Series I
  - Addresses
    - Chronological, 1915-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1-12)
    - Chronological, 1937-1946, undated (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - Associates, 1935-1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Community nursing, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "The Leadership of a Great Objective", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Nursing education, 1942, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "The Social Responsibility of Women", undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Addresses and papers, 1925-1927, undated (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - American Journal of Nursing, 1936-1949 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - American Nurses Association
    - Bulletins and reports, 1934-1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1916, 1940-1948 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
    - Minutes, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Army School of Nursing
    - General, 1918-1948 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1928-1948 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Frazer, Margaret, 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Stimson, Julia, 1925-1934 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Photographs, 1921-1928 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Reopening, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Suspension, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Association of College Schools of Nursing
    - Addresses, 1940, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Constitution and by-laws, 1934-1946 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Bolton, Chester (Mrs.), 1934-1940 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Burgess, Elizabeth C., 1933-1936 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Gowan, Olivia, 1934-1941 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Howell, Marion, 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Resignation, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Stewart, Isabel M., 1932-1935 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Titus, Shirley, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Executive Committee, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Financial reports, 1934-1938 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Membership Committee, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Memberships: delegates, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Minutes, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Proceedings of Conferences
      - Conference I, 1933-1937 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Conference II, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Programs for Conferences, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Reports on Nursing Schools
      - General, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Catholic University of America, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - Cornell-New York Hospital, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Duquerne University, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Standards, 1931-1936 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Standards report: Catholic Hospital Association, 1934. (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Beard, Mary: "Nursing Needs", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Birthday: 80th celebration, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 62-63)
  - Birth control, 1936-1941 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Book lists, undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Catalogues: books, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Calvalcade of America: "Militant Angel", 1951 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Colorado State Teachers College
    - General, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Curriculum study, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Community Nursing Service, 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Community Survey: Kepler, Aura E., 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Connecticut League of Nursing Education, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence
    - Personal, 1930-1952, undated (Box 6, Folder 74-76)
    - Miscellanea, 1930-1949 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Diary, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Equal Rights legislation, 1931-1944 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Florence Nightengale International Foundation
    - By-laws and objectives, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1930-1935 (Box 7, Folder 81)
      - American Nurses Association, 1934-1948 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Education Committee, 1933-1950 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Financial reports, 1935-1937 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Minutes
      - American Nurses Association, 1935-1948 (Box 7, Folder 84)
      - Reports, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - News bulletins, 1934-1952 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Pamphlets, 1940-1948 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Report, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Miscellanea, 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Health insurance, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Henry Street Settlement, 1913-1935 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Institute of Living
    - Minutes, 1945-1948 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Pamphlets, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Psychiatric nursing, 1935-1953 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - International Council of Nurses
    - Bedford College Report, 1935-1937 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Board of Directors
      General
      See: box 15, folders 199-202
    - Bulletin, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Constitution and by-laws, 1933-1946 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1949 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Educational reports, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Financial reports, 1946-1947 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Membership Committee, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Report to Grand Council, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Unofficial conference, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Miscellanea, 1945-1947 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - "Journey to Yale", 1939 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Lecture reference material, undated (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Medals
    General note
    See: box 20
  - Michigan Children's Health Fund, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Michigan League of Nursing Education, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Minnesota, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 110-111)
  - National Advisory Committee for Community Service Projects, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 112-118)
  - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1935-1950 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - National Health Plan, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - National Institute of Social Science, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - National League of Nursing Education, 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 122-123)
  - New Haven Hospital, 1919-1938 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - New Jersey League of Nursing Education, 1934-1935 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - New York-Cornell Medical Center
    - Committee on Nursing Education, 1928-1930 (Box 10, Folder 126-127)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1914-1947 (Box 10, Folder 128-131)
      - Beard, Mary, 1929-1935 (Box 10, Folder 132)
      - St. John, Ethel, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 133)
      - Wolf, Anna, 1931-1932 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Nurse Liscense Bill, New York state, 1914-1919 (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - Nursing Education
    - General, 1928-1939 (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - Administration, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Book lists, undated (Box 10, Folder 138)
    - Community nursing, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 139)
    - Hospital statistics, 1923-1940 (Box 10, Folder 140)
    - Isolation, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 141)
    - Lectures and pamphlets, 1930-1940 (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - Lovett report to A.M.A., 1923 (Box 11, Folder 143)
    - Nursing 93, 1931-1934 (Box 11, Folder 144)
    - Requirements and standards, undated (Box 11, Folder 145)
    - Trends in nursing, 1934-1936 (Box 11, Folder 146)
  - Nursing in national defense, 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 147)
  - Nursing service, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 148)
  - Pamphlets, 1932-1946 (Box 11, Folder 149-150)
  - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania area report, 1934-1935 (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - Presbyterian Hospital, New York, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - Public Health, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 153)
  - Public Health nursing: Minnesota, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 154)
  - Public Health nursing report: Tennant, Mary E., 1935 (Box 11, Folder 155)
  - Red Cross
    - General, 1931-1941 (Box 12, Folder 156)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1941 (Box 12, Folder 157)
    - Reports, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Report of Committee to create an Educational Plan to Meet the Needs of Government Services, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Reprints of Articles
    - American Journal of Nursing, 1930-1946 (Box 12, Folder 160)
    - Goodrich, A.W., 1929-1930 (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Rockefeller Foundation
    - European Tour, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 162)
    - European Tour Report, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - St. Louis, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - Student Term Papers, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - University of California School of Nursing, 1933-1934 (Box 12, Folder 166)
  - University of Connecticut, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 167)
  - Western Reserve
    - Community Service Nursing Summer Course, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 168)
    - School of Nursing, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 169)
  - White House Conference on Nursing Education, undated (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Wisconsin, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Works Progress Administration
    - General Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 172)
    - Agriculture, 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 173)
    - Arts Service project, 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 174)
    - Commissioners letters and bulletins, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 175)
    - Defense, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 176)
    - Miller, J. Howard, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 177)
    - National Advisory Committee for Community Service Projects, 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 178)
    - Pamphlets and newspaper clippings, 1923-1941 (Box 13, Folder 179)
    - Public health, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 180)
    - Statistics, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 181)
    - States
      - Alabama, 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 182)
      - Connecticut, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 183)
      - Illinois, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 184)
      - North Carolina, undated (Box 13, Folder 185)
      - Tennessee, 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 186)
      - Wisconsin, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 187)
  - Yale School of Medicine, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 188)
  - Yale School of Nursing
    - General, 1929-1940 (Box 14, Folder 189)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1952 (Box 14, Folder 190)
    - Graphs and statistics, 1932-1935 (Box 14, Folder 191)
    - "I Remember When", 1946 (Box 14, Folder 192)
    - Reports, 1926-1927 (Box 14, Folder 193)
    - Student reports, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 194)
    - Tribute, Class of 1935-1936, undated (Box 14, Folder 195)
    - 25th Anniversity exercises, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 196)
  - Miscellanea (Box 14, Folder 197)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 14, Folder 198)
  - International Council of Nurses: Board of Directors, 1935-1939 (Box 15, Folder 199-202)
    See also: boxes 7-8, folder 80
- PHOTOGRAPHS AND MEMORABILIA, Series II
  - Printed material
    - Army School of Nursing: Annual, 1921 (Box 16, Folder 203)
    - Florence Nightingale International Association: Japan, undated (Box 16, Folder 204)
    - Grady Hospital: Training project, undated (Box 16, Folder 205)
    - State Charities Aid Association, New York, 1876-1877 (Box 16, Folder 206)
    - Tributes, 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 207)
  - Photographs
    - Goodrich, Annie Warburton (Box 17, Folder 208)
    - Groups (including A.W. Goodrich) and hospitals (Box 17, Folder 209-211)
    - Oversize: groups (including A.W. Goodrich) (Box 18)
  - Memorabilia
    - Portrait (painting) and certificates (Box 19)
    - Medals (Box 20)